suncor.com 2005-12-30

# Suncor.com :: Legal Notice

Following are the disclaimers, terms and conditions for use of the Suncor Energy Inc. web site and, by using this web site, you are accepting that you are bound by the disclaimers, terms and conditions set forth below. 

References to "Suncor Energy Inc.", "Suncor" and "the company" shall include Suncor Energy Inc., Suncor Energy Foundation and our subsidiaries, including Suncor Energy Products Inc. and Suncor Energy Marketing Inc. (SEMI). Please note that Suncor Energy Inc.'s subsidiary, Suncor Energy Products Inc., is an Ontario, Canada, corporation that uses the Sunoco brand and is a separate and unrelated company from Sunoco, Inc., Philadelphia, U.S.A., corporation. Any references to "Sunoco" refer only to the Ontario downstream brand, which is part of Suncor Energy Products Inc.

 **Disclaimer**

Suncor does not warrant or make any representations or claims as to the validity, accuracy, currency, timeliness, completeness or otherwise of the information contained in this web site, nor shall it be liable or responsible for any claim or damage, direct, indirect, special, consequential or otherwise arising out of the interpretation, use or reliance upon, authorized or unauthorized, of such information.

The content in this web site may not always be the most current source of the company information, and Suncor disclaims liability for any failure to update this web site or the information or any material document contained therein. In addition, the information and materials available on this web site are not intended to provide specific legal, accounting, financial, investing or tax advice to any user. The documents and information available on this web site are provided as a convenience only and, where any documents on this web site have been filed in accordance with applicable securities laws, such documents are not the official versions of Suncor's disclosure documents, and the user is directed to obtain official copies either from applicable securities regulators or from the company.

Internet software transmission problems could produce inaccurate or incomplete copies of documents or other material from this web site when downloaded or displayed on a user's computer, and Suncor takes no responsibility for the accuracy or completeness of documents or material downloaded or displayed from this web site. 

Suncor takes reasonable precautions to ensure this web site is free from computer viruses, however, it is recommended that the user install and use appropriate anti-virus or other protective software. Suncor disclaims liability for any computer viruses or other destructive programs that may be inadvertently downloaded from this web site.

This web site may contain certain forward-looking statements that are based on Suncor's current expectations, estimates, projections and assumptions and are made by the company in light of its current experience and its perception of historical trends. All statements that address expectations or projections about the future, including statements about Suncor's strategy for growth, expected expenditures, commodity prices, costs, schedules and production volumes, operating or financial results, are forward-looking statements. These statements are not guarantees of future performance and involve a number of risks, uncertainties and assumptions. Suncor's actual results may differ materially from those expressed or implied by its forward-looking statements as a result of known and unknown risks, uncertainties and other factors. Discussion of the risks, uncertainties, assumptions and other factors that could affect Suncor's plans and any actual results are described in Suncor's Annual Report, Management's Discussion and Analysis and other documents filed with Canadian and U.S. securities regulatory authorities.

 **Ownership of Material**

The material and information on this web site is being made available only under the conditions set out herein. Suncor reserves rights to the intellectual property presented in and by this web site, which includes, but is not limited to, our copyrights, trademarks and corporate logos. "Suncor" is a Canadian-and U.S.-registered trademark, and "Sunoco" is a Canadian-registered trademark of Suncor and our affiliated companies.

No material from this web site may be copied, reproduced, republished, uploaded, posted, transmitted or distributed in any way, except that you may download one copy of the materials on any single computer for your personal, non-commercial home use only, provided you keep intact all copyright and other proprietary notices. Modification of the materials or use of the materials for any other purpose is a violation of Suncor's copyright and other proprietary rights. You may not frame this web site nor link to this web site without Suncor's express permission. If you wish to link to this web site, please contact us at [info@suncor.com](mailto:info@suncor.com).

 **Privacy**

At Suncor, we are committed to protecting the privacy and security of the personal information of individuals with whom we interact, such as our customers, suppliers, neighbours, employees and contractors. 

**Privacy Principles**

_Collecting, Protecting and Using Information_

When collecting personal information from individuals, we will explain how we intend to use it, we will collect only what we believe is reasonably necessary to meet those purposes, and will not use or disclose it for other unrelated purposes without the person’s consent, except in the limited circumstances prescribed by applicable law. Upon inquiry, we will explain the options for, and consequences of, withholding or withdrawing consent, and will record and respect an individual’s choices. Suncor may also collect from another party, such as a service provider or other organization, personal information from or about an individual, if the individual has provided his or her consent to the other party, allowing Suncor to collect and use the individual’s personal information. 

Our business processes will be designed and applied to appropriately safeguard personal information, considering the sensitivity and use of that information. We will make reasonable efforts to ensure information is as accurate and up-to-date as is reasonably necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. Once the information is no longer needed, it will be appropriately destroyed.

_Sharing Information_

We may provide an individual’s personal information to other parties:  

  * where we have the individual’s consent 
  * where required or permitted to by law 
  * where the other parties are acting as our agent or as a service provider and have agreed to handle the information in accordance with this policy, or 
  * where business mergers, divestments or acquisitions are involved.

We may collect personal information about an individual from other parties: 

  * where we have the individual’s consent; 
  * where required or permitted to by law 
  * where the other parties are acting as our agent or service provider and have agreed to handle the information in accordance with this policy 
  * where business mergers, divestments or acquisitions are involved, or 
  * where the other party has obtained the individual’s consent.

_Access to Information_

Individuals may request access to the information that Suncor has about them, may discuss Suncor’s business practices regarding the use of the information, and may address concerns about how Suncor handles personal information, by contacting a Suncor Privacy Officer – (403) 269-8151.  We respect the concerns of individuals regarding information about them, and will respond to concerns or complaints within a reasonable timeframe and within the timeframe required by law. 

**What is Personal Information?**

Personal information is any factual or subjective information about an “identifiable individual”. It can include: 

  * name 
  * home address 
  * e-mail and phone number 
  * resume information 
  * age 
  * purchases and spending habits 
  * photos 
  * credit card information 
  * opinions 
  * evaluations, or 
  * comments. 

Personal information does not include anything that might appear on business cards or can be found through other publicly available information, such as a telephone directory. The legislation also does not cover personal information used strictly for personal purposes (such as personal greeting card lists) or for journalistic, artistic or literary purposes. 

**Privacy While Using Suncor's Internet Sites**

For technical evaluation and statistical purposes, Suncor employs per-session cookies on our web site.  This mechanism collects the name of the individual’s Internet Service Provider, IP (Internet protocol) address and server name, the length of each visit, the number of requests per visit, and the individual’s operating system and browser type.  No attempt is made to correlate these details with personal information that an individual submits voluntarily. 

If web site users provide Suncor with personal information through Internet use or e-mail, the company will consider that consent to use this information for the purpose it has been provided has been granted to Suncor, its affiliates or agents.  For example, resumes are used for employment purposes; contact information provided through the subscribe feature is used to provide alerts of new information on the site as requested by the user. Once an individual unsubscribes, their user-ID is deleted from the list. 

Suncor also scans Internet communications for system management and security purposes in order to detect malicious software and unauthorized access. Privacy and confidentiality are not guaranteed when using unencrypted Internet communications.

In some cases, Suncor uses third parties to process transactions that may include personal information. In such cases, we rely on contract terms and conditions with third parties to ensure they apply the same or higher standards concerning collection, use and disclosure, as were identified in Suncor’s privacy policy. We will also pass relevant personal information to others where we are legally entitled or required to do so. 

**Other Terms & Conditions**

Certain links on this web site lead to sites maintained by independent parties over whom Suncor has no control. Suncor makes no representation as to the accuracy or any other aspect of the information contained on such sites, and Suncor disclaims all liability and responsibility for the content of such sites.

All monetary amounts mentioned in this web site are in Canadian dollars unless otherwise noted.

Use of this web site, including disclaimers, terms and conditions set out herein, shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the Province of Alberta, Canada, and the courts of the Province of Alberta, Canada, shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising out of your use of this web site.

**To Find Out More**

If you would like more information about Suncor’s privacy practices, or to request access to your personal information, please contact us:

By e-mail: [Suncor Information](mailto:info@suncor.com)

By telephone: (403) 269-8100 or toll-free 1-866-SUNCOR-1 (1-866-786-2671) 

By mail:  Suncor Energy Inc.  
              P.O. Box 38, 112 - 4 Avenue S.W.   
              Calgary, Alberta   
              Canada T2P 2V5

Please direct your inquiry to a Suncor privacy officer:

  * Employee / contractor inquiries - Colleen Timlick, manager, Suncor Employee Centre 
  * External inquiries - Patti Lewis, director, External Communications

Suncor's chief privacy officer is Janice Odegaard, vice president, associate general counsel and corporate secretary.
